Guide to the Fred Chappell Papers, 1944-2019 and undated RL.00213
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Oversize Material, 1963-1997 and undated
  - Writings by Chappell Series, Essays Subseries
    - Taking Sides: Six Poetry Anthologies (1994, Georgia Review), galley proof, 1994 Apr. 28 (Box OM-1)
  - Writings by Others Series
    - Maiolo, Joseph, Elverno (1972), proof (Box OM-1)
    - Unknown author, Structure of Prejudice, proof, unpublished, ca. 1960-1969 (Box OM-1)
  - Miscellaneous Series
    - Apron labeled Fred Chappell Creative Writing Cooking: Recipes from the Authors You Love, undated, rec'd 1995 July (Box OM-2)
    - Broadside, A Curtain Rises, by Chappell, 1993 June 26, Numbers 14, 27-30 of 100 (Box OM-2)
    - Broadside, East Carolina University 1990 chancellor's Forum, 1990 Jan. 4 (Box OM-2)
    - Broadside, Lullaby: the Comforting of Cock Robin, from W.D. Snodgrass, Selected Poems: 1957-1987, Number 53 of 200, inscribed to "Fred and Susan" by the author (Box OM-2)
    - Broadside, poem Alligator Holes Down Along About Old Dock, by A.R. Ammons, an unnumbered copy of 500 printed, 1993 June 26 (Box OM-2)
    - Folder of writings and drawings by class at Orange High School, Hillsborough, N.C., in reaction to I Am One of You Forever, 1988 Mar. 2 (Box OM-2)
    - Poster, Duke Writing: The William Blackburn Legacy, undated Nov. 4-5 (Box OM-2)
    - Poster, Fifth annual Spring Literary Festival, 1990 May 9-12, 2 copies (Box OM-2)
    - Poster, The Barton College Creative Writing Symposium, featuring Fred Chappell and Louise Shivers, 1997 Mar. 20 (Box OM-2)
    - Poster, Voices of the South, 1994 (Box OM-2)
    - Serial, Saturday Evening Post, May 9, 1964, with story by Chappell, A Property of Hope (Box OM-2)
    - T-shirt inscribed by The Nomad staff, undated, rec'd 1995 July (Box OM-2)
- Accessions, 1993-2018
  Scope and Contents
  Annual additions to the Fred Chappell Papers that have been processed to varying degrees - these materials are available for research but description and physical condition is inconsistent. Includes incoming and outgoing correspondence (at times in original envelopes); writings and drafts by Chappell; materials from various events, publications, engagements, and organizational commitments he held; and writings by others, often including Chappell's annotations or responses drafted on the packaging. Other items may include audiovisual and electronic records, artwork, ephemera, or souvenirs. Arranged and boxed by accession.
  - Accession (1993-0102)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
    - John Crews Pelot: An Autobiography. Bradenton, Fla.: 1992. Inscribed to Chappell by the author. (Box 1)
    - Incoming correspondence with attachments (including writings by the correspondents), 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - Accession (1998-0299)
    Conditions Governing Access
    [Electronic records in this collection have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room.]
    Correspondence, writings, speeches, books, and other materials, mainly from the years 1997-1998.
    - Correspondence Sent, 1997-1998, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 3)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 5)
    - Writings and Speeches, ca. 1997-1998, 8 folders (Box 6)
      Typescripts, holographic manuscripts, and notes for poetry, prose and fiction writings. Includes page proofs for A Way of Happening.
    - Publications: journals, miscellaneous printed materials, videocassette (1) (Box 6)
    - Publications: books (19), audio cassette (1) (Box 7)
    - Dragon, 1995; 1 3.5" floppy disk image; approximately 2 megabytes.
    - Awards and Memorabilia (Box 8)
    - Printed Materials (Box 8)
  - Accession (1999-0202)
    Some of the materials are not immediately accessible because they require further processing before use. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Library to use this collection.
    - Writings by Chappell (Box 1)
    - Writings by Chappell and others (Box 2)
    - Incoming correspondence (Box 3)
    - Incoming correspondence (Box 4)
    - Incoming correspondence (Box 5)
    - Incoming correspondence (Box 6)
    - Outgoing correspondence (Box 6)
    - Printed materials (Box 6)
    - Printed Materials (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous materials (Box 7)
    - Ovsz. materials: writings, printed materials, clippings, videotape, photographs, and miscellaneous (Box 8)
    - Ovsz. materials: writings, printed materials, clippings, videotape, photographs, and miscellaneous (Box 9)
    - Awards and publicity (Box OM-3)
  - Accession (2000-0272)
    This accession covers the years 1989-2000. Some of the materials are not immediately accessible because they require further processing before use. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Library to use this collection.
    Chappell often wrote letter replies and/or notes on the outsides of the envelopes. These are found primarily in box 7.
    - Professional correspondence (Box 1)
    - Smoke and Gravity by Win Niagle, manuscript (Box 1)
    - Ray and Rosa Hicks, "The Last of the Old-Time Story Tellers," video (Box 2)
    - Professional correspondence (Box 2)
    - Personal correspondence (Box 2)
    - Survivor by Valerie Nieman, manuscript (Box 2)
    - Excerpt on Chappell from Contemporary Authors (Box 2)
    - Catalogs from Presses (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous serials: The Southern California Anthology, Carolina Quarterly, Now and Then (The Appalachian Magazine), Sky (Delta Airlines), Here at Appalachian, Duke Magazine, Southern Living, American Literary History. (Box 2)
    - Professional correspondence (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous serials: Shenandoah, The Seattle Review, UNC-Greensboro Magazine, Brightleaf (Box 3)
    - This is Where I Live: 100 Years of North Carolina Poetry by Brenda P. Schleunes, manuscript (Box 3)
    - Recommendation materials for Adam C. Hall (Box 3)
    - Programs and flyers for miscellaneous readings and events (Box 3)
    - Every tree is the forest, poems by Emöke Zsuzsánna B'Rácz (Box 3)
    - Cassette tapes: Jim Clark / Now and Then, Dr. R. Orlowski, Grace, Frank, Eleanor, and Mary Rollman interview with James Kibler (Box 3)
    - Professional correspondence (Box 4)
    - Personal correspondence (Box 4)
    - Photocopies of letters written by Chappell (Box 4)
    - Proposal for course entitled "Science and Literature" (Box 4)
    - UNC-G guidelines for course proposals (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous writings by Chappell including book reviews, speeches, essays, and poems (Box 4)
    - Moonjox, manuscript (Box 4)
    - Notebooks containing drafts of literary works, letters, notes (Box 4)
    - Look Back All the Green Valley, original manuscript (Box 5)
    - Personal correspondence (Box 5)
    - Professional correspondence (Box 5)
    - Personal correspondence (Box 6)
    - Professional correspondence (Box 6)
    - Materials for North Carolina Poetry Society anthology (Box 6)
    - Bright Corners, by Bob Clark, manuscript (Box 6)
    - Last of the Mohicans by Michael Mann, screenplay manuscript (Box 6)
    - Printed materials (Box 6)
    - Professional correspondence (Box 7)
    - Oversize materials, primarily correspondence and some printed materials (Box 8)
    - Poster addressed to Chappell from a Draper Elementary School class (Box OM-3)
  - Accession (2001-0145)
    - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Books and Manuscripts by other authors (Box 1)
    - Newsletters and Newspaper Clippings (Box 1)
    - Loose and Unlabeled Material (Box 1)
    - Correspondence (Box 2)
    - Last Days of Big Grassy Fork by Hunter James (Box 2)
    - Loose Material (Box 2)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Unlabeled folders (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Greyhound God by Keith Morris (Box 6)
    - Unlabeled Folders (Box 6)
    - Unlabeled folders (Box 7)
    - Correspondence (Box 7)
    - Correspondence (Box 8)
    - Correspondence (Box 9)
    - Newspaper Clippings (Box 9)
    - Correspondence (Box 10)
    - Unlabeled folders (Box 10)
    - Books (Box 11)
    - Unlabeled folders (Box 11)
    - Magazines (Box 12)
    - Books (Box 12)
    - CDs (Box 12)
    - Videocassette Tapes (Box 12)
    - Printer's proof for The Wild Boy by Warren Rochelle (Box 12)
    - Correspondence (Box 12)
    - Script for Chappell's Brighten the Corner Where You Are (Box 12)
  - Accession (2002-0171)
    This accession contains sensitive information (student recommendations) in boxes 11 and 13. Patrons must sign a waiver concerning privacy rights. Contact Research Services.
    - Photographs (Box 1)
    - Printed Material, 1954-1986
      - Writings by Chappell (Box 1)
      - The Archive, 1954-1962 (Box 1)
      - Features, Awards, Reviews (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
    - School Report Cards, 1944-1949 (Box 1)
    - North Carolina Award in Literature, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Awards, Events, Items about, Reviews, Writings, Correspondence, 1955-2002, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Duke University BA Diploma, 1961 (Box 2)
    - Duke University MA Diploma, 1964 (Box 2)
    - Chanticleer, 1961 (Box 2)
    - Incoming Correspondence, 2001 Feb.-Aug. (Box 3)
    - Incoming Correspondence, 2001 Aug.-Oct. (Box 4)
    - Incoming Correspondence, 2001 Oct.-Dec. (Box 5)
    - Incoming Correspondence, 2001 Dec.-2002 Jan. (Box 6)
    - Incoming Correspondence, 2002 Feb.-Mar. (Box 7)
      Includes an uncorrected proof of On a Wave by Thad Ziolkowski.
    - Incoming Correspondence, 2002 Apr.-May (Box 8)
    - Incoming Correspondence, 2002 Apr.-June (Box 9)
    - Incoming Correspondence, 2002 June-Aug. (Box 10)
    - Incoming Correspondence, undated (Box 10)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1999 May-2002 June (Box 11)
    - Hollow Ground, MS. by Stephen Marion (Box 11)
    - Common Wealth, MS., edited by R. T. Smith and Sharah Kennedy, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Articles, Chappell, News and Observer, 5 folders (Box 12)
    - Other Newspaper Articles, Chappell (Box 12)
    - Newspaper Items about Chappell (Box 12)
    - [Loose materials: miscellaneous drafts of Chappell's work], 5 folders (Box 12)
    - Loose Material, miscellaneous drafts of Chappell's work (Box 13)
    - Notebooks, Miscellaneous Drafts, Chappell, 5 folders (Box 13)
    - Loose material: copies of Chappell's work in various journals. (Box 13)
    - Legal-size Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 13)
    - 7 audiocassettes; 1 Betamax and 3 VHS videocassettes; and 1 audio CD (Box 14)
      Includes recordings of Chappell with George Garrett, as well as of Chappell reading his work.
    - Watercolor and accompanying correspondence removed from box 5. (Box OM-3)
    - Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box OM-3)
    - Posters re: Chappell (Box OM-3)
  - Accession (2003-0089)
    - Journals, magazines, and newspapers, 2002-2003 (Box 1)
    - Framed literary award to Chappell, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 2002 June-2003 May (Box 2)
    - Journals and magazines, 2002-2003 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 2002 June-2003 May (Box 3)
    - Collections of poetry and prose sent to Chappell by other writers (Box 3)
    - Chappell's handwritten poetry diaries (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 2002 Aug.-2003 Mar. (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 2002 Aug.-2003 May (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 2002 July-2003 Mar. (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 2002 July-2003 Jan. (Box 7)
    - Drafts of Chappell's poems, plays, articles, and talks (Box 7)
    - Photocopy of poetry anthology edited by Chappell (Box 7)
    - Chappell's handwritten literary diaries (Box 8)
    - Drafts of Chappell's poems, plays, articles (Box 8)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 2002 June-2003 May (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 9)
    - Framed awards to Chappell, 2002-2003 (Box 10)
    - Literary Festival poster (Box 10)
  - Accession (2004-0127), 9 boxes, 1 oversize folder
    Addition (2004-0127) (3165 items, 6.0 lin. ft; dated 2003-2004 and n.d.) consists mainly of Chappell's personal and professional correspondence (2003-2004). Also includes notebooks and loose papers containing drafts of poems and other writings by Chappell; clippings and other printed materials; and writings by other authors.
  - Accession (2006-0024), 16 boxes
    Addition (2006-0024) (4942 items, 9.6 lin. ft.; dated 1978-2004 and undated) comprised chiefly of personal correspondence; drafts of unidentified writings by Chappell; notebooks; a plaque, Appalachian Heritage Writer's Award, 2004; a signed print, "Birthday Poems," by David R. Slavitt; and clippings. This accession is closed to researchers.
  - Accession (2006-0071), 14 boxes, 2 oversize folders
    Addition (2006-0071) (970 items, 9.8 lin. ft.; dated 1987-2006 and undated) comprises primarily correspondence (2005-2006), as well as notes, clippings, manuscripts for review, Chappell's draft poems, books, serial issues, one VHS videocassette, awards, posters, and ads. This accession is closed to researchers.
  - Accession (2010-0223), 3 boxes
    Addition (10-223) (2625 items; 3.5 lin. ft.; dated 2006-2010 and no date) includes incoming and outgoing correspondence; writings by other authors; clippings; published materials by Chappell; and prose and poetry drafts by Chappell. Also includes correspondence regarding the Caldwell medal, awarded to Chappell by the North Carolina Humanities Council in 2010.
    - Bound volumes (Box 1)
      - Published Writings by Chappell
        - Fresh Deliveries: New Translation of Rimbaud and Char, Asheville Poetry Review 17.1, 2010 (Box 1)
        - Literary Trails of the North Carolina Piedmont: A Guidebook, 2010 (Box 1)
          Includes excerpts of Fred Chappell's work.
        - Articles of Faith, Convergence Review 2.1, Summer 2010 (Box 1)
        - Anemone, Fresh...Stories, Poems, Ideas, Spring 2010 (Box 1)
        - Uncle Moon in Raintree Hills, Fantasy and Science Fiction, Sept/Oct. 2010 (Box 1)
        - First Encounters, Eudora Welty: Writers' Reflections Upon First Reading Welty, 2010 (Box 1)
        - Russian translation of a Chappell work (Box 1)
      - Published Writings by Others
        - Planet Stories, 2010 (Box 1)
    - Drafts by Chappell
      - Letters (Box 1)
      - Prose, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Poetry (Box 1)
    - Writings by Others
      Arranged alphabetically by author. Most writings are unpublished drafts that are accompanied by correspondence for Chappell, either asking for a review or for comments on the draft. Many books have been withdrawn for individual cataloging. Please consult the last folder in the subseries for these titles.
      - Anne Blythe: Carolina Mountain Song, 2010 (Box 1)
      - Harry Brown: In Some Households the King is Soul: Poems, 2010 (Box 1)
      - Kathryn Byer: Descent, 2010 (Box 1)
      - Duane Carr: A Question of Class, 1996 (Box 1)
      - Catherine Carter: The Swamp Monster at Home, 2010 (Box 1)
      - Rene Char, translated by Nancy Naomi Cadson: Stone Lyre (Box 1)
      - Sharon Chmielarz: The Sky is Great, The Sky is Blue; Calling, 2010 (Box 1)
      - Darin Cozzins: Light of the New Day, 2010, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Julia Nunnally Duncan: At Dusk, 2010 (Box 1)
      - George Ivey: Up River, 2009 (Box 1)
      - Larry Johnson: Veins, 2009 (Box 1)
      - Michael Kent: In Pursuit of Liberty, 2010 (Box 1)
      - Guy H. Lillian III, 2010 (Box 1)
      - Linda P. Marion: Bound, 2010 (Box 1)
      - Llewellyn McKernan: Pencil Memory, 2010 (Box 1)
      - Arthur Rimbaud: The Illuminations; A Season in Hell, 2007-2009 (Box 1)
      - Warren Rochelle: The Called, 2010 (Box 1)
      - Ed. M. Schorb: The Journey, 2010 (Box 1)
      - Rose Senehi: The Wind in the Woods, 2010 (Box 2)
      - Nancy Simpson: Living Above the Frost Line, 2010 (Box 2)
      - Jillian Weise: The Colony, 2010, 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Withdrawn books and accompanying correspondence, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence
      - Outgoing, March 2010-December 2010, 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Incoming, 2006-2008 (Box 3)
      - Incoming, April 2009-December 2009, 6 folders (Box 3)
      - Incoming, 2010, 17 folders (Box 3)
      - Incoming, undated (Box 3)
      - Incoming Caldwell Medal correspondence from the North Carolina Humanities Council, 2010 (Box 3)
    - Clippings about Chappell, 2009-2010 (Box 3)
    - Oversize posters from the North Carolina Literary Festival, 2009 (Box OM-3)
  - Accession (2007-0121), 15 boxes
    Addition (2007-0121) (4875 items, 8.8 lin. ft.; dated 2000-2007) contains correspondence, drafts, books, and serials. The majority of the correspondence consists of review copies of books and drafts by other authors and requests for blurbs or reviews by Chappell.
    - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Drafts of Chappell's poems, articles, and stories (Box 1)
    - Professional correspondence (Box 2-5)
    - Blurb requests and drafts by other authors (Box 2-5)
    - Professional correspondence (Box 6)
    - Printed letters by Chappell (Box 7)
    - Professional correspondence (Box 8-10)
    - Typescript of M.D. Brown's A Counting of Crows (Box 11)
    - Professional correspondence (Box 11)
    - Untitled typescript (Box 12)
    - Correspondence (Box 12)
    - Correspondence (Box 13)
    - Typescript of The Rhythm Method, Razzmatazz and Memory by Keith Flynn (Box 14)
    - Watercolor painting by Jeffrey Reddick (Box 14)
    - The Blue Chair by David Schenk (Box 15)
    - Blueprints (Box 15)
  - Accession (2008-0096), 7 boxes, 1 oversize folder
    Addition (08-096) (3375 items; 4.5 lin. ft.; bulk dated 2007-2008) includes notebooks, drafts, and manuscripts of essays, stories, poetry, and speeches; correspondence; and some printed materials. Also includes some electronic media (floppy disks of Chappell drafts), which have been removed and copied to Duke's electronic server. This accession has not been processed.
    - Typed drafts of Chappell's essays and poetry (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Drafts of Chappell's speeches and public remarks (Box 1)
    - Printed materials: science fiction journals and literary review journals, 1981-2007 (Box 1)
    - Notebooks with handwritten drafts and notes (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 2007-2008 (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 2007-2008 (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Notebooks, legal pads, and loose papers with Chappell's handwritten drafts and notes (Box 2)
    - Incoming correspondence, 2007-2008 (4 folders) (Box 2)
    - Incoming correspondence, 2007-2008 (Box 3-4)
    - Incoming correspondence, 2007-2008 (7 folders) (Box 5)
    - Incoming books, manuscripts, and poetry (Box 5)
    - Incoming books, manuscripts, and poetry by other authors (Box 6-7)
      Arrangement note
      (Includes drafts and published versions of works by Chappell's friends and colleagues, often accompanied by correspondence. These materials have not been foldered.)
    - Incoming correspondence (Box OM-3)
    - Digital materials, 2006-2008; 3 DOC document files; approximately 1 megabyte.
      Includes 'Christmas Gift!', 'The Invading Spirit', and 'The White Cat'.
  - Accession (2008-0321), 1 folder
    Chappell's annotated proof (1990) copy of the Selected Poems of William Gillmore Simms.
  - Accession (2009-0144), 5 boxes, 1 oversize folder
    Addition (2009-0144) (3600 items; 4.8 lin. ft.; dated 2005-2009) includes correspondence, writings, manuscripts by other authors, and some printed materials. Also includes some electronic media (floppy disks of Chappell drafts).
    - Correspondence, 2008-2009 (18 folders) (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 2008-2009 (13 folders) (Box 2)
    - Outgoing correspondence (3 folders) (Box 2)
    - Writings (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Writings (8 folders) (Box 3)
    - Other author manuscripts
      - Unlabelled (Box 3)
      - Rob Amberg (Box 3)
      - Wiley Cash (Box 3)
      - Katherine De Lorraine (Box 3)
      - Julia Nunnally Duncan (Box 3)
      - Jeffrey Franklin (Box 3)
      - James Kibler (Box 3)
      - David Middleton (Box 3)
      - E.M. Schorb (2 folders) (Box 3)
      - Allen Speer (Box 5)
    - Printed materials
      - Pembroke Magazine 40, 2008 (Box 5)
      - Sewanee Review, Summer 2008 (Box 5)
      - Fantasy and Science Fiction, Oct.-Nov. 2008 (Box 5)
      - Fantasy and Science Fiction, Feb. 2009 (Box 5)
      - ABZ 4, 2009 (Box 5)
    - Magazines, 2008-2009 (Box 5)
    - Appalachian Songbook advertisements and correspondence (Box OM-3)
    - University of North Carolina at Greensboro honorary doctorate, 2008 (Box OM-3)
    - Digitial materials, 2006-2008; 4 document files and 3 image files; approximately 31 megabytes.
      Includes 'Dance of Shadows', 'The Crooked Shadow', 'The Diamond Shadow', 'The Keeper Shadows', and 'Thief of Shadows'.
  - Accession (2010-0106), 9 boxes
    Addition (10-106) (4000 items; 5.4 lin. ft.; dated 2006-2010 and no date) includes correspondence, writings by other authors, and essays, prose, poetry, and other drafts by Chappell. Also includes some electronic media (some CDs sent to Chappell by fellow authors).
    Correspondence has been sorted by month and year.
    - Other author writings (Box 1)
      - What a Body Needs, Jim Stokely (5 folders) (Box 1)
      - One Page at a Time, Pat Carr (2 folders) (Box 1)
      - UMBRA 2009 (Box 1)
    - Fred Chappell's writings and drafts (Box 2)
      - Remnants (Box 2)
      - Things Beyond Us (Box 2)
      - Poetry (Box 2)
      - Prose and short stories (Box 2)
      - Spiral notebook with drafts and notes (Box 2)
      - Essays, letters, etc. (Box 2)
      - Fletcher Lecture Series cookbook, 2009 (Box 2)
      - Prose (Box 3)
    - Printed/published works by Chappell
      - Thief of Shadows. The Magazine of Fantasy and Science Fiction, vol. 118.5-6, May/June 2010. (Box 3)
      - Slecna Prue (Soucasna jizanska literatura 1). Aluze Revue pro literaturu, filozofii a jine, Jedna, 2003. (Box 3)
      - David Bottoms and the Evolution of the Gob Aesthetic. The Sewanee Review, vol. CXVII, no. 4, pg. 592. (Box 3)
      - Go Along to Get Along. Modern Age, vol. 51.2, Spring 2009. (Box 3)
      - The Mystery and Adventure Series Review, no. 44, Summer 2009. (Box 3)
      - The Hymn Disclosed. The Anglican Theological Review, vol. 91.3, Summer 2009. (Box 3)
      - Proper Respect. Smoky Mountain Living, vol. 9 no. 5, pg. 64. (Box 3)
      - Still Learning from Him: A Tribute to Robert Watson, Fall 2009. (Box 3)
    - Outgoing correspondence, May 2009-May 2010 (Box 3)
    - Incoming correspondence (Box 4)
      - April 2009-July 2009 (Box 4)
      - July 2009-October 2009 (Box 5)
      - October 2009-December 2009 (Box 6)
      - January 2010-March 2010 (Box 7)
      - March 2010-May 2010 and undated (Box 8)
      - Oversize incoming correspondence, May 2009-March 2010 and undated (Box 9)
  - Accession (2012-0031), 5 boxes
    Addition 2012-0031 includes incoming and outgoing correspondence; writings by other authors; published materials by Chappell; and prose and poetry drafts by Chappell. Also includes a flat box of oversized materials taken from incoming correspondence.
    - Correspondence Series (Box 1)
      - Incoming, December 2010-February 2012, 20 folders (Box 1)
      - Incoming, undated, folder 1 of 3 (Box 1)
      - Incoming, undated, folders 2-3 of 3 (Box 2)
      - Outgoing, January 2011-February 2012, 14 folders (Box 2)
      - Oversized Incomming Correspondence, 2010-2012 (Box 5)
    - Writings by Chappell (Box 2)
      - Drafts: Poetry, 4 folders (Box 2)
      - Drafts: Prose, 3 folders (Box 2)
      - Maze of Shadows (Box 2)
      - Bound volumes and journals, 5 folders (Box 2)
    - Writings by Others (Box 2)